# software engineering leader

# mike roberts

☑ miker@miker.org ⑤ miker.org ⑥ 508.579.4478 ᠺ ecopoesis

I am a software leader with two decades experience managing and growing cloud platforms and software as a service products.

I am active proponent of building scalable, well tested, service oriented architectures. I have led the development numerous platforms over my career, in a variety of languages ranging from the terrible (PHP 5) to the sublime (Scala). I champion moving quickly and smartly. I have taken multiple products from slow, buggy, waterfall to fast, agile, daily releases.

I have run everything from focused, technical tiger teams to entire engineering organizations with dozens of ICs and line managers.

# experience

#### Indigo Agriculture

Principal Engineer (Manager and Architect)

Charlestown, MA 2019 - Current

I manage Indigo's back office settlements team. We have pioneered high availability, 24/7 uptime services at Indigo. As one of Indigo's architects I introduced reactive patterns and built a widely-used message bus to asynchronously connect our microservices.

## Salsify

Principal Engineer (Manager)

Boston, MA 2016 - 2019

At Salsify I led the platform services team, developing the shared infrastructure and code used by Salsify's application teams. Notable accomplishments include building an asynchronous job system and the first wave of Salsify's GraphQL APIs.

#### TripAdvisor Vacation Rentals

Principal Engineer

Boston, MA 2015 - 2016

Ported legacy FlipKey and Holiday Lettings property management systems to newly designed, unified system.

#### Leaf Holdings

Software Engineering Manager (Director)

Cambridge, MA

I lead both the Android and platform teams, enhancing the existing proof-of-concept to scale to 100k transactions per second. I hired dozens of engineers including a fully remote team in Istanbul. I worked with my engineers to design a distributed, eventually consistent data-store co-homed on our Android tablets in the field and on AWS.

#### Smarter Travel Media

Software Engineering Manager (Director and Architect)

Designed and built a database system as part of WebEx's SaaS offering.

Built and lead the Tingo team, spinning up a new online travel agency in 9 months. Led hiring across the STM engineering organization. Ran the architectural review board.

### Cisco Systems

Software Engineering Manager

Burlington, MA

Charlestown, MA

## education

#### Worcester Polytechnic Institute

### skills

#### expert

- Scala
- Java
- Ruby
- Python
- GraphQL
- MySQL
- Postgres
- Kafka
- Redis
- Maven
- SBT
- git

- BS Theatre
- BS Computer Science

# experienced

- Javascript
  - PHP
  - C# / .NET
  - SQL Server
  - Kubernetes
  - AWS
  - Terraform
  - Puppet

# faq

#### Star Trek or Star Wars?

Star Trek

#### Marvel or DC?

DC

#### Vim or Emacs?

• Vim

#### Narnia or Middle Earth?

• Middle Earth

#### Kanban or Scrum?

• Kanban, but every team is different

#### Kirk or Picard?

• Janeway